ABUBAKAR SADIQ SAMBO

sadiqasg@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

A graduate of Business Administration and a Software Developer with experience in building professional client products and working on projects with Government Ministries and Agencies. I've worked with Front End technologies and have working experience with Back End / Server-Side technologies and Databases.

Portfolio: https://sadiqsambo.netlify.app Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/sadiqsambo

EXPERIENCE

September 2021 – Present STUTERN

Intern Software Engineer

Responsible for building APIs and other Backend services.

- **Technologies**: NodeJs (ExpressJs), Typescript, MongoDB, PostgreSQL.
- **Tools:** Github (code repository/version control), ESlint, Prettier (Code formatters) Slack (team communications).

July 2019 - Present

PUBLIC AND PRIVATE DEVELOPMENT CENTER (PPDC)

Software Developer

Responsible for building client-facing applications for in-house products and partner products.

- **Technologies**: HTML, CSS, Javascript jQuery, NodeJs, Firebase.
- **Tools:** Github (code repository/version control), Figma Design, WhatsApp (team communications).

March 2019 - April 2019

INTELLECTUAL APPS LTD.

Web Developer - Contract

Collaborated in building a taxation app that calculates Company tax and Personal Income Tax.

- **Technologies**: HTML, CSS, jQuery, Java.

- **Tools:** Bitbucket (code repository/version control) and Slack (team communications).

November 2018 - January 2019

UNICEF - MINISTRY OF HEALTH

CMAM Data Monitor:

Monitored data of selected facilities, record stock and Interview the head of each OTP facility on how they handle cases. Also, where needed, offer a guide on best practices and how to properly record data of malnutrition cases.

June 2018 - October 2018

TANN TECHNOLOGIES

Frontend Developer.

Responsible for designing mock-ups and building the client-facing implementation.

- **Technologies**: Javascript Angular(6)
- **Tools:** Figma Design, Bitbucket (code repository/version control) and Slack (team communications).

April 2018 - June 2018

HOTELS.NG

Remote Software Developer Intern

Collaborated with UI designers and Backend developers, in teams, to carry out tasks following project specifications.

- Technologies: HTML, CSS, PHP, Bootstrap.
- Tools: Slack, Github, Teamviewer, Pivotal Tracker.

June 2015 - May 2016

DIALOGUE COMPUTER INSTITUTE, KADUNA

Administrative Assistant – Registrar's Office (NYSC PPA)

EDUCATION

In-Progress (Dec 2022)

STUTERN ACCELERATOR

Software Engineering

In-Progress (Dec 2022)

EDX | HARVARDX ONLINE CS50

Web programming with Python and Javascript

Awarded 2020

UDEMY

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

Awarded 2019

OPENCLASSROOMS

Certificates in Software Engineering (HTML, React, Node, and Express)

Awarded 2018

ANDELA LEARNING COMMUNITY WITH MICROSOFT

Computer Programming – Frontend Web Developer Course

Awarded 2016

NIGERIAN INSTITUTE OF MANAGEMENT (CHARTERED)

Proficiency Certificate in Management

Awarded 2015

UNIVERSITY OF ABUJA, FCT

B.Sc. Business Administration

Final Year Research Project: The role of small and medium-scale enterprises in the economic development of Nigeria.

Awarded 2008

AIR FORCE COMPREHENSIVE SCHOOL UYO, AKWA IBOM

Senior Secondary School Certificate

Awarded 2002

FTMC NURSERY AND PRIMARY SCHOOL FESTAC, LAGOS

Primary School Leaving Certificate

OTHER CERTIFICATIONS

- Go Full-stack with Node.js, Express, and MongoDB Openclassrooms.
- Frontend Web Developer Course ALC with Microsoft.
- Certificate of Computer Science OAU Consultancy Services Center, Suleja.

SKILLS

SOFT

Good verbal and written communication skills, Teamwork and Team management skills, Critical thinking and creativity

TECHNICAL

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, MUI, JavaScript, Jquery, React, NodeJs (ExpressJs), Python - Django (Basic), Typescript, SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Figma

SPOKEN LANGUAGES

Proficient in English and Hausa languages.

- Limited proficiency in Yoruba and Arabic.Basic Deutsche (Learning).